CHRIS JORDAN

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Well-rounded professional with experience at the intersections of data, system administration, and analytics. Familiarity with several programming languages, including bash, Python, and SQL, and experience working with and analyzing large datasets using a variety of DBMS back-ends and statistical packages.

EDUCATION

May 2011 University of Maryland, College Park Bachelor of Arts, Economics

EXPERIENCE

July 2014-Present

Blue Labs Washington, DC

- △ Deployed and maintained Vertica in AWS
- Administered production databases for political campaigns and critical government programs
- ♣ Designed storage architecture for Blue Labs' historical survey data
- ▲ Deployed production environments in AWS for Blue Labs' analytical environment
- ▲ Developed automated deployment scripts for development and production environments
- Developed scripts in Airflow to scrape election data
- ▲ Developed storage strategy for large volumes of slowly changing data
- △ Wrote internal data syncs using Airflow and Kubernetes

April 2012-June 2014

Votes, Voices, Now Washington, DC

Deputy Director of Targeting and Analytics

- A Provided analytics support and development to America Votes and its partner organizations to aid in decisionmaking and resource allocation, particularly during the 2012 elections
- Developed an IVR polling application using Python, Amazon AWS,

- and web service APIs
- △ Developed a web-based program using Django to track and manage campaign activity across multiple partner organizations
- ▲ Built issue support models from polling, voter file, and commercial data using R
- Automated ETL processes to populate databases with polling and other data for reporting and analysis

February 2012-April 2012 Change Coordinator

Bowles Fluidics Columbia, MD

- Analyzed the financial and logistical impact of revisions to finished goods
- △ Orchestrated and facilitated cross-team integration in production change processes

October 2011-February 2012 Bowles Fluidics Columbia, MD Jr. Industrial Engineer

- △ Optimized and documented production processes relating to plastic hose extrusion
- Programmatically generated Advanced Product Quality Planning (APQP) documents in Excel

January 2011-October 2011 Bowles Fluidics Columbia, MD Excel Analyst

- Wrote reports for dissemination to technical and non-technical personnel
- ▲ Wrote an application to schedule production plans using VBA
- Wrote an application to manage nonconformance data using VBA
- Automated reporting on inventory and labor statistics

SKILLS

Vertica
Bash
Python
MySQL
Amazon AWS
Linux
Docker
Concourse

Ansible
Git
Django
PostgreSQL
Web service APIs
Apache Airflow
Kubernetes
Terraform